# Aleksandr (Alex) Stepanov | Full-Stack Software Developer

403-399-3035 | stepanov.hw@gmail.com | stepanovcodes.netlify.app in/aleksandr-stepanov | github.com/stepanovcodes

#### SUMMARY

I am a results-oriented, agile-driven Software Engineer, focused on UX design and end-users' needs in fast-paced and demanding environment. 5 years of Canadian and international software product management and technical sales experience, supplemented with petroleum engineering background, informs everything that I do: from my ability to adjust plans quickly to finding efficient, concise solutions for challenging problems, ensuring optimal outcomes for both product users and business growth.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Languages: HTML | JavaScript | EJS | CSS | Python | SQL | VBA

**Libraries and Frameworks:** Node.js | Express | React | Next.js | jQuery | TypeScript | TailwindCSS | Bootstrap | Sequelize | OAuth 2.0 | Django | Fluent 2

**Utilities:** CLI | Git | GitHub | VS Code | Mongoose | MongoDB | PostgreSQL | Postman | openAl API | RESTful API | AWS | Chrome DevTools | Jira | Figma | Slack | Trello | Zoom | WITSML | WITS

**Product Management:** Agile Methodology | Software Development Lifecycle | Eliciting Requirements | Roadmaps | Agile Sprint Planning | Reviews & Metrics

### RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Route Finder | Solo Project (deployed, in progress)

Full-Stack Developer | 1 week | Live | Github

- The app assists users in submitting routing problems and subsequently visualizes the solutions on a map
- Built with JavaScript, REACT, TailwindCSS, Fluent 2, MongoDB, Mongoose, Express, Node.js, and Mapbox API
- The application leverages the new Mapbox Optimization v2 algorithm to retrieve routing problem solutions based on numerous inputs and constraints, and it displays them on the map

## Theme Generator I Team Project

PM and Backend Developer | 1 week | Live | Github

- Enhanced by AI, the app generates and previews styles exclusively based on theme names and descriptions
- Built with JavaScript, EJS, CSS, MongoDB, Mongoose, Express, Node.js, Bootstrap, OpenAI, Passport
- The application leverages the OpenAl API to translate textual theme names and descriptions into JSON-like styles, which are then rendered onto the page. Google OAuth2.0 is implemented to authenticate user identities, determine permissions, and secure the routes

## Video Poker I Solo Project

Web Developer | 1 week | Live | Github

- The game requires a player to achieve a hand of at least a pair of Jacks or a higher-ranking combination to win
- Built with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and Bootstrap framework. It follows the MVC design architectural pattern
- Ul faithfully replicates the graphics of real casino Video Poker and adapts seamlessly to various screen sizes

## Solo Box & Solo WITSML Store | Rogii Canada Ltd.

Product Owner | 2 years | Website

- These two products aggregate and transmit well data from rig to office in real-time. Commercialized in 2021
- Built with JavaScript, React, CSS, PostgreSQL, C#. Enhanced with Fluent Design System. Deployed on AWS
- "Solo Box" leverages websocket data transmission to ensure minimal lag time. "Solo WITSML Store" complies with the Energistics WITSML 1.4.1.1 standard, which is broadly recognized in Oil & Gas Industry. The product also parses email attachments and connects with third-party rig data providers

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## **Software Product Owner**

Calgary, AB

Rogii Canada Ltd. 2021 - 2023

- Launched and commercialized two software products in Canada, the USA, Australia, Latin America, and Kazakhstan
- Practiced the SCRUM Agile methodology through sprint planning, daily scrums, sprint reviews, sprint retrospectives
- Managed product roadmaps and backlogs of about 3,000 Jira issues for three independent teams consisting of ten developers, three QA specialists, one designer, and one business analyst
- Expressed requirements using user stories, story maps, and acceptance tests; visualized the requirements using wireframes and storyboards
- Ensured an accessible foundation by using Fluent's design system, which meets or surpasses WCAG 2.1 AA standards
- Formed a product support team consisting of four technical analysts and conducted ongoing evaluations of support tickets to gather feedback on the products
- Traveled to various locations, including rigs in the USA and Canada, to facilitate equipment installation

## **Technical Sales**

Calgary, AB

Adaga Solutions, Ltd 2019 - 2021

- Promoted geosteering software, drilling analytics software, and WITSML server for Oil & Gas industry
- Finalized sales in Americas, collected the feedback on software products, determined business opportunites
- Performed troubleshooting, care about a customer (personal visits to customer sites, in-house training, online meetings, and telephone/email correspondence)

### **EDUCATION**

General Assembly Remote

Software Engineering Immersive

expected to be awarded in October 2023

 In this intensive 420-hour program at General Assembly's Bootcamp, I'm gaining hands-on experience in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, React, Node.js, Express, MongoDB. I honed my skills in responsive design, API integration, secure authentication, and Agile methodologies. This comprehensive program is fostering my collaboration, problem-solving, and critical thinking abilities while enabling me to build a professional portfolio of full-stack web applications

University of Alberta Remote

Software Product Management Specialization

July 2023

• In this four-month specialization, I mastered Agile software management practices to lead a team of developers and interact with clients from inception to delivery. In the final Capstone Project, I practiced and applied management techniques to realistic scenarios related to software processes, requirements, planning, and improvements to create better software products

## Southern Alberta Insitute of Technology

**Calgary, AB** 2017-2019

Bachelor of Applied Technology in Petroleum Engineering Honors / Entero Energy Software Award Winner

Heriot-Watt University Edinburgh, UK

Master of Science in Petroleum Engineering Honors

2011-2012